Shen Yan

Email: yanshen6@msu.edu Homepage: shenyann.github.io

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Michigan State University 1228 Engineering Building East Lansing, MI 48824

Highlights

My research centers on unsupervised learning and AutoML. This fits well with a nascent and fast-evolving research field referred to as **Neural Architecture Search**, which aims to automate deep learning model design and reduce the cost of manually designed deep learning models across different use cases. My work covers the entire spectrum of research in this domain: from building efficient optimization algorithms to search specialized neural network on cheap mobile devices, to understand architecture encodings and its clustering effect through theoretical analysis and empirical evaluations.

Education

| Michigan State University, East Lansing, USA Ph.D., Computer Science, 3.8/4.0 | Jan 2019 - now |
|---|-----------------------|
| RWTH Aachen University, Aachen, Germany M.S., Computer Engineering, 1.2/5.0 (excellent) Xidian University, Xi'an, China B.S., Electrical Engineering, 3.82/4.0 | Oct 2018 July 2015 |
| | |
| Top Reviewers of ICML '20 | Sep 2020 |
| 4th Place Winner of NeurIPS '19 Google MicroNet Challenge | Nov 2019 |
| ICCV '19 Neural Architects Workshop Best Paper Award Nominee | Oct 2019 |
| MSU Graduate Office Fellowship (GOF) | Jan 2019 |
| World Finalist, Kaggle Data Science Game, Paris | Sep 2016 |
| Summer School Exchange Student, Tsinghua University | Aug 2015 |
| Meritorious Winner, International Mathematical Contest In Modeling (MCM) | May 2014 |
| First Prize Scholarship, Xidian University | Sep 2012, 2013 |
| Professional Experiences | |
| Applied Machine Learning Intern TikTok, Mountain View, USA | June 2020 - Sep 2020 |
| Research Intern | May 2019 - Aug 2019 |
| Bosch Research, Sunnyvale, USA | |
| Research Intern eBay Research, Aachen, Germany | Apr 2017 - Aug 2017 |
| Software Engineering Intern Nuance Communications, Aachen, Germany | Aug 2016 - Oct 2016 |
| Teaching Assistant RWTH Aachen University, Aachen, Germany | Oct 2015 - Feb 2016 |
| | |

Publications

- [8] **Shen Yan**, Yu Zheng, Wei Ao, Xiao Zeng, Mi Zhang. "Does Unsupervised Architecture Representation Learning Help Neural Architecture Search?". In *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS' 20)*, Online, Dec 2020.
- [7] Taojiannan Yang, Sijie Zhu, **Shen Yan**, Mi Zhang, Andrew Willis, Chen Chen. "MutualNet: Adaptive ConvNet via Mutual Learning from Network Width and Resolution". In *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV '20)*, Online, Aug 2020. [Oral Presentation]
- [6] **Shen Yan**, Huan Song, Nanxiang Li, Lincan Zou, Liu Ren. "Improve Unsupervised Domain Adaptation with Mixup Training". In *arXiv:2001.00677*., Cornell University Library, January 2020.
- [5] Abin Jose*, **Shen Yan***, Mi Zhang, Jens-Rainer Ohm. "Deep Subclass Linear Discriminant Analysis for Multimodal Feature Space Learning". In the Proceedings of *IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP '20)*, Online, October 2020.
- [4] Shen Yan, Biyi Fang, Faen Zhang, Yu Zheng, Xiao Zeng, Hui Xu, Mi Zhang. "HM-NAS: Efficient Neural Architecture Search via Hierarchical Masking". In the Proceedings of *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV '19) Neural Architects Workshop*, Seoul, Korea, October 2019. [Best Paper Award Nominee]
- [3] Shen Yan, Leonard Dahlmann, Pavel Petrushkov, Sanjika Hewavitharana, Shahram Khadivi. "Word-based Domain Adaptation for Neural Machine Translation". In the Proceedings of *The International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT '18)*, Bruges, Belgium, October 2018. [Oral Presentation]
- [2] Abin Jose, **Shen Yan**, Iris Heisterklaus. "Binary Hashing Using Siamese Neural Networks". In the Proceedings of *IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP '17)*, Beijing, China, September 2017.
- [1] Harald Hanselmann, **Shen Yan**, Hermann Ney. "Deep Fisher Faces". In the Proceedings of *The British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC '17)*, London, UK, September 2017.

Patents

- [1] "Systems And Methods For Implementing Flexible, Content-adaptive Deep Learning Neural Networks". U.S. Provisional Application
- [2] "System And Method on Improving Unsupervised Domain Adaptation with Mixup Training". U.S. Provisional Application

Selected Media Coverage

MSU Today [Science & Technology]. 'MSU Team focused on AI earns recognition at Google MicroNet Challenge"

Jan 2020

JiQiZhiXin. "ICCV Workshop Best Paper Nominee: Efficient Neural Architecture Search via Hierarchical Masking"

Oct 2019

Professional Services

Journal Reviewer

Neurocomputing 2020

Conference Reviewer

ICML 2020, NeurIPS 2020, ICLR 2021

Skills

Programming Language

Python, Go, C/C++, Perl, Lua, Bash/Shell, Make, HTML.

Language

English, German, Chinese.

Frameworks

NumPy, Pandas, Tensorflow, PyTorch, SciPy, Caffe, Moses, OpenCV, Scikit-Learn, OpenGL, Git.

Systems

Linux, OSX.